Guide to the Colton Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
More information concerning these and other members of the Colton family can be found in the following:
Select Correspondents of Henry M. Colton
Day, H. N. 1867 Aug 28
Evarts, William M. 1859 Sep 10, 1863 Oct 26
Foster, Dwight 1860 Jul 10
Gibbs, Josiah W. (Y1809) 1858 Feb 5, Jul 8, 1859 Aug 6
Gibbs, Josiah W. (Y1858) 1861 Apr 7, 1864 Jan 18, Feb 10
Green, Horace, M.D. 1862 Oct 4, Nov 30, Dec 20, 1863 Mar 8, Apr 27, May 6, Jun 2, Jul 10, Sep 10, Oct 24
Hadley, James 1858 May 7, Nov 9, Mar 6, 1860 Jul 6, Dec 29, 1862 Feb 25, 1863 May 25, Sep 9, Sep 24, 1864 Mar 9
Herrick, Edward C. 1860 Aug 13
Jewell, Marshall 1864 Dec 2, Feb 13, 1866 Jul 16
Perkins, Samuel C. 1860 Sep 7
Pomeroy, S. C. 1864 Jun 22, Feb 13
Porter, John A. 1860 Jan 17
Porter, Noah (Y1831) 1858 Nov 23, 1863 Sep 6, 1865 Sep 19, 1867 Jul 8
Seymour, Thomas H. 1867 Jan 18, Apr 20, Jul 29
Sheffield, Joseph E. 1860 Aug 18, Sep 8, Sep 13, Sep 20, Dec 11, Dec 21, 1861 Aug 2
Shipman, Nathaniel 1864 Jan 1, Feb 14, Nov 17
Silliman, Benjamin (Y1796) 1858 Nov 29, Dec 3, 1859 Jun 20, 1860 Dec 24
Silliman, Benjamin (Y1837) 1866 Aug 3
Stowe, Harriet Beecher 1867 Sep 3
Thacher, Thomas 1859 Jun 4, 1861 Nov 23, 1862 Jan 4, Sep 5, 1863 Sep 2, Sep 21, 1865 Aug 26
Varnum, Joseph 1862 Apr 25, 1863 Jul 18, Jul 24
White, Henry 1860 Oct 30
Woolsey, Theodore Dwight 1852 Oct 3, 1858 Feb 5, 1863 Sep 10, 1867 Jun 17
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Education; Families; Sermons; Diaries; Clergy; Educators; Colton, George H. (George Hooker), 1818-1847; Colton, George, 1736-1812?; Colton, George, 1779-1858; Colton, Henry M. (Henry Martyn), 1826-1872; Colton, Horace, d. 1862; Colton, John Owen, 1810-1840; Colton, Lucy Tuttle, 1826-1897; Evarts, William Maxwell, 1818-1901; Gibbs, J. Willard (Josiah Willard), 1839-1903; Gibbs, Josiah W. (Josiah Willard), 1790-1861; Green, Horace, 1802-1866; Hadley, James, 1821-1872; Porter, Noah, 1811-1892; Sheffield, Joseph Earl, 1793-1882; Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864; Thacher, Thomas Anthony, 1815-1886; Woolsey, Theodore Dwight, 1801-1889; Colton family; Cowles family; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1848; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory, 1749, 1826-1879, undated
  - [George Colton, 1736-1812?]
    - Booklet on surveying, 1749 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - George Colton, 1779-1858
    - Religious writings, 1855, 1857-1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Owen Colton, 1810-1840
    - Orations and prose writings, 1827-1828 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Addresses, essays and other writings, 1832-1835 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Lecture notes, poems and other writings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Notebook containing names of Yale freshmen, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - [John Owen Colton, 1810-1840?]
    - Sermons and notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Dr. Nordheimer's Lectures to the Seminary", Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Horace Benjamin Colton, 1816-1862
    - Account book, poem, 1829-1830, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - George Hooker Colton, 1818-1847
    - Orations, poems, translations, 1840, [1846?], undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Manuscript, contract and printed matter re: The American Review, 1844, 1849, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Henry Martyn Colton, 1826-1872
    - Diaries, 1840, 1842-1843 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Pre-college translations, [pre-1845] (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - College disputes, Circa 1848 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Translations and travel writings, 1842, 1848, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - College lecture notes, 1847, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Poems, 1839-1848, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Compositions and notes, 1839-1851 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Solemn covenant vows with Jehovah...", 1840 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Ministry recommendation, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Sermons, 1851-1857 (Box 2, Folder 21-23)
    - Sermons and sermon notes, 1852-1855, 1864, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Sermon notes and outlines, 1855-1856 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Sermon fragments, 1862, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Addresses, translations, book list, 1868, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Notes on religion and philosophy, Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Notebook containing names of Yale students, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "Notes on Rev. Dr. Fitch's Lectures on Homiletics," and notes on classmates, Undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - [Henry Martyn Colton, 1826-1872?]
    - Miscellaneous notes and essays, Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Lucy Tuttle (Mrs. Henry Martyn) Colton, 1826-1897
    - Probate records, 1827-1850 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - [Lucy Tuttle (Mrs. Henry Martyn) Colton, 1826-1897?]
    - Recipe, poems and meditations, Undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - [Willis Strong Colton, 1828-1908?]
    - Notebook containing names of Yale freshmen, 1850 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence
    - 1795 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - 1826-1831 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - 1832 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 1833-1834 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - 1835 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - 1836-1839 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - 1843-1844, 1849 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - 1850-1854 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - 1855-1859 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - 1860-1861 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - 1862-1863 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - 1864-1872 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Miscellany
    - Invitations, calling cards and notes, 1859, 1860, 1866, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Colton and Cowles family genealogies, Undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Poems by unidentified authors, 1843, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Writings by unidentified authors, Undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Mathematics notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1856, 1863, 1866, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 55)